Welcome to this module on Introduction to Data Analysis with Python.
In this module, you&#39;ll learn about an example around estimating used car prices that we
will analyze in this course, using Python.
Then we will introduce an overview of Python packages used for data analysis.
And finally, you will learn about how to import and export data in and from Python, and how
to obtain basic insights from the dataset on used cars and their prices.
So to learn how to analyze data in Python, we&#39;ll be answering the following question:
&quot;Can we estimate the price of a used car based on its characteristics?&quot;
To answer this question, we are going to use various Python packages to perform data cleaning,
exploratory data analysis, model development and model evaluation.